Register of the Stanislaw Mikolajczyk Papers, 1899-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1941-1965
  - Speeches
    - 1953
      - July
        - "Analysis of Events behind the Iron Curtain" (Folder 11)
        - "People's Democracy in Theory and Practice" (Folder 12)
      - August-September (Folder 13)
    - 1954
      - General
        - General - Itinerary (Folder 14)
        - February-April (Folder 15)
        - May-June (Folder 16)
        - September-December (Folder 17)
      - "Can Russia Depend upon the Armies of Its Satellites?" Economic Club of Detroit, January 25
        - General (Folder 18)
        - Clippings (Folder 19)
        - Correspondence (Folder 20)
        - Proceedings (Folder 21)
        - Programs of other events (Folder 22)
    - 1955 (Folder 23)
    - 1956
      - January-April (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - May-July (Folder 2)
      - August-November (Folder 3)
    - 1957
      - January-June (Folder 4)
      - August, "The United Nations and the Communist Oppressed Peoples of Central-Eastern Europe" (Folder 5)
      - September (Folder 6)
    - 1958
      - General (Folder 7)
      - May-June (Folder 8)
    - 1959 (Folder 9)
    - 1962 (Folder 10)
    - 1963
      - General (Folder 11)
      - January-June (Folder 12)
      - September-October (Folder 13)
  - Statements
    - 1954 (Folder 14)
    - 1956 (Folder 15)
    - 1957
      - General (Folder 16)
      - Polish elections (Folder 17)
  - Writings
    - General
      - 1949 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - 1950 (Folder 2)
      - 1953
        - Narodowiec (Folder 3)
        - World Jewish Congress (Folder 4)
      - 1957 (Folder 5)
      - 1962 (Folder 6)
      - 1964 (Folder 7)
      - 1965 (Folder 8)
    - "Communism in Poland," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
    - "The Coming Russian Terror," installments, 1948. Typescript (Folder 10)
    - "Poland in Chains," 1948. Typescript (Folder 11)
    - The Rape of Poland, 1948
      - Correspondence
        - 1948 (Folder 12)
        - 1949 (Folder 13)
        - 1950 (Folder 14)
        - 1954 (Folder 15)
      - Drafts
        - First
          - Part 1 (Folder 16)
          - Part 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
          - Part 3 (Folder 2)
          - Part 4 (Folder 3)
          - Part 5 (Folder 4)
        - Second
          - Part 1 (Folder 5)
          - Part 2 (Folder 6)
          - Part 3 (Folder 7)
          - Part 4 (Folder 8)
        - Final
          - Part 1 (Box 22, Folder 1)
          - Part 2 (Folder 2)
          - Part 3 (Folder 3)
          - Part 4 (Folder 4)
          - Part 5 (Folder 5)
      - Outline of chapter contents
        - First edition (Folder 6)
        - Second edition (Folder 7)
      - Publicity excerpts (Folder 8)
      - Reviews
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Czech (Folder 10)
        - English (Folder 11)
        - French (Folder 12)
        - German (Folder 13)
        - Italian (Folder 14)
        - Polish émigré
          - General (Folder 15)
          - Polish-American (Folder 16)
      - Supporting material - Poland's internal situation (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "Komunizm przeciw chlopom," 1949 ?
      - Notes (Folder 2)
      - Typescript (Folder 3)
    - "Zza zelaznej kurtyny" ("Zycie za zelazna kurtyna"), 1949
      - Clippings (Folder 4)
      - Typescripts (Folder 5)
    - "The Struggle of Communism against the Catholic Church in Poland," 1953. Typescript (Folder 6)
    - "Libraries, Bibliographies, Books: Tools in the Communistic Education of the Polish People," 1953. Typescript (Folder 7)
    - "Sovietization of Poland after World War II," 1953 Typescript (Folder 8)
    - "Soviet Problems in Poland," 1954
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Holograph (Folder 10)
      - Typescript (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Zagadnienia polskie," 1955
      - Notes (Folder 2)
      - Typescript
        - English (Folder 3)
        - Polish (Folder 4)
    - Narod Polski w Walce o Wolnosc I Niepodleglosc, 1956-1957 a Leninowska taktyka: Jeden Krok w Tyl Dwa Kroki Naprzod, 1957
      - Typescript (Folder 5)
      - Galleys of English translation, n.d. (Folder 6)
- GOVERNMENT SERVICE FILE, 1940-1946
  - Komitet Ministrow dla Spraw Kraju (Ministerial Committee for the Country's Interior Affairs), 1939-1942 [Member]
    - Correspondence
      - 1939
        - November (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - December (Folder 2)
      - 1940
        - January (Folder 3)
        - February (Folder 4)
        - March (Folder 5)
        - April (Folder 6)
        - May (Folder 7)
        - June (Folder 8)
        - July (Folder 9)
        - August (Folder 10)
        - September (Folder 11)
        - October (Folder 12)
        - November (Folder 13)
        - December (Folder 14)
      - 1941
        - January-March (Folder 15)
        - April-June (Folder 16)
        - July-September (Folder 17)
        - October-December (Folder 18)
      - 1942 (Folder 19)
    - Reports from Poland, 1941
      - January-March (Folder 20)
      - July - Soviet atrocities in Poland (Folder 21)
      - September - Polski Komitet Opiekunczy w Warszawie (Folder 22)
  - Ministerstwo Edukacji/Ministerstwo Wyznan Religijnych i Oswiecenia Publicznego (Ministry of Education)
    - Kaczynski, Zygmunt, 1942-1944 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Organizational structure, 1945 (Folder 2)
  - Ministerstwo Informacji i Dokumentacji (Ministry of Information and Education) [Deputy Minister]
    - Correspondence, 1940-1944 (Folder 3)
    - Log books
      - 1942 September 12-1943 March 30 (Folder 4)
      - 1943 March 29-December 31 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Radio bulletins, 1941-1944 (Folder 2)
    - Reports
      - Hunger in Poland, 1940 (Folder 3)
      - Polish campaign in the Middle East (Folder 4)
      - Soviet-American, Soviet-British treaties 1942 (Folder 5)
      - Ukrainians in North America, 1940 (Folder 6)
  - Ministerstwo Obrony Narodowej-Ministerstwo Spraw Wojskowych (Ministry of Defense)
    - Brochures - Airforce, 1940-1947 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - 1940 (Folder 2)
      - 1942. Includes intelligence reports (Folder 3)
      - 1943 (Folder 4)
    - Reports, 1940
      - Antigovernment agitation (Folder 5)
      - Army, Reorganization of (Folder 6)
      - France, Evacuation from (Folder 7)
      - German prisoner of war camps (Folder 8)
      - Miranda de Ebro (Folder 9)
      - Segiega, Napoleon, Escape to Polish army (Folder 10)
    - Sosnkowski, Kazimierz file
      - General
        - 1940
          - General (Folder 11)
          - Polish underground, Struggle within (Folder 12)
        - 1941
          - General (Folder 13)
          - Zwiazek Walki Zbrojnej. Report to Sikorski (Folder 14)
        - 1942 (Folder 15)
        - 1943 (Folder 16)
        - 1945 (Folder 17)
      - Printed matter, 1953-1955 (Folder 18)
  - Ministerstwo Pracy i Opieki Spolecznej (Ministry of Labor and Social Welfare), 1940-1943 (Folder 19)
  - Ministerstwo Skarbu (Ministry of Finance) - Relocation of gold, 1939-1941 (Folder 20)
  - Ministerstwo Spraw Kongresowych (Ministry of Preparatory Works)
    - General - Przeglad Literatury Politycznej. Issues
      - 1941 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - 1943 October (Folder 2)
    - Airforce, 1944 (Folder 3)
    - Biuro Prac Administracyjnych i Studium Prawno Administracyjne
      - General
        - List (Folder 4)
        - Nos. 1-5 (Folder 5)
        - Nos. 6-8 (Folder 6)
        - Nos. 9-12 (Folder 7)
        - Nos. 13-15 (Folder 8)
        - Nos. 16 (Folder 9)
        - Nos. 17-18 (Folder 10)
        - Nos. 19-26 (Folder 11)
        - Nos. 27-33 (Folder 12)
      - "Administracja publiczna w Szkocji," 1942 (Folder 13)
      - "Organizacja wladz administracji ogolnej w pierwszej dobie okresu powojennego," 1942 (Folder 14)
      - "Projekt zmian w ustroju samorzadu terytorialnego na tle zmian form administracji przyszlego panstwa polskiego," 1942 (Folder 15)
    - Central and South-Eastern Europe, 1942 (Folder 16)
    - Curzon Line, 1945 (Folder 17)
    - Eastern territories, Annexation of
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 18)
      - 1944 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Elections regulations, 1943-1944 (Folder 2)
    - Europe
      - Federalism, 1943 (Folder 3)
      - Future of
        - 1941 (Folder 4)
        - 1944 (Folder 5)
    - Germans - United States, 1942 (Folder 6)
    - Germany
      - Disarmament, 1943 (Folder 7)
      - Economy, 1944 (Folder 8)
      - Peace treaty with
        - 1941 (Folder 9)
        - 1942 (Folder 10)
      - Population transfer, 1942 (Folder 11)
      - War reparations, 1941 (Folder 12)
    - International policy, 1943 (Folder 13)
    - Harriman's economic interest in Poland and Germany, n.d. (Folder 14)
    - Maritime war aims, 1943 (Folder 15)
    - New Europe Circle (Allied Circle)
      - General
        - General (Folder 16)
        - List (Folder 17)
        - Documents, nos. 1-88 (Folder 18)
        - Writing by W. Loeb, entitled "Truce, Armistice and Peace," 1944 (Folder 19)
      - Members (Folder 20)
      - Polish Soviet relations, 1943 November (Folder 21)
    - Orthodox Church, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Poland
      - Agriculture
        - List (Folder 2)
        - Nos. 1-65. Includes "Polski wywoz rolniczy po wojnie" (Folder 3)
        - Nos. 66-133. Includes "Postulaty rolnicze do traktatu pokojowego" (Folder 4)
        - Nos. 134-150. Includes "Natychmiastowe zarzadzenia rekonstrukcji powojennej rolnictwa" (Folder 5)
        - Nos. 151-180 (Folder 6)
        - Nos. 181-221. Includes "Elektryfikacja wsi" (Folder 7)
        - Nos. 222-269 (Folder 8)
      - Borders
        - General, 1943 (Folder 9)
        - Eastern, 1943-1944 (Folder 10)
        - Western
          - General, 1942-1943 (Folder 11)
          - Underground's point of view, 1943 (Folder 12)
      - Economic system, 1943 (Folder 13)
      - Frontiers in course of history (Folder 14)
      - Place and tasks in post-war history, 1941 (Folder 15)
      - Political system, 1944 (Folder 16)
      - Post-war aims and position, 1943 (Folder 17)
    - Polish-Czechoslovak relations in exile, 1943 (Folder 18)
    - Polish Government Information Center, 1944 (Folder 19)
    - Post-war international order, 1943 (Folder 20)
    - Underground resistance and plans for insurrection, 1941 (Folder 21)
    - United Nations Relief and Reconstruction Administration. Purchases plan, 1944 (Folder 22)
  - Ministerstwo Spraw Wewnetrznych (Ministry of Interior) [Minister]
    - General
      - Appeals
        - General, 1940-1941 (Box 32, Folder 1)
        - "Do Kobiet," 1940 (Folder 2)
        - "Litania do Swietej Barbary," n.d. (Folder 3)
      - Correspondence
        - Hungarian diplomat? Anonymous letter from Berlin, 1943 October 28 (Folder 4)
        - Kremerowski (Komitetet Zagraniczny Polskiej Partii Socjalistycznej), 1943 (Folder 5)
      - Documents on Western borders - "Slowa krytyki deklaracji Rady Jednosci Narodowej," 1944 (Folder 6)
      - Press file
        - Émigré
          - Komunikat Informacyjny, nos. 1-2, 1940 (Folder 7)
          - Skaut, 1944 August (Folder 8)
        - Underground
          - General
            - Press reviews - Przeglad Prasy Krajowej
              - 1943 September-1944 February (Folder 9)
              - 1944 May-June (Folder 10)
            - Reports from Poland
              - Sikorski, Wladyslaw - Death (Folder 11)
              - S.O.S., 1944 (Folder 12)
          - Agencja A, 1944 May (Folder 13)
          - Agencja Blok Srodkowo Europejski, 1944 April (Folder 14)
          - Agencja Europa Srodkowa, 1944 April (Folder 15)
          - Agencja Prasowa, 1944 (Folder 16)
          - Biuletyn Informacyjny
            - 1940-1941 (Folder 17)
            - 1944 (Folder 18)
          - Biuletyn Informacyjny. Materialy Informacyjne, 1943-1944 (Box 33, Folder 1)
          - Demokrata, 1944 June (Folder 2)
          - Dzien Warszawy, 1944 April (Folder 3)
          - Gwardia Ludowa, 1943 August (Folder 4)
          - Insurekcja, 1944 January (Folder 5)
          - Kalendarz KOP-u, 1941 (Folder 6)
          - Kraj, 1944 (Folder 7)
          - Mlodziez Socjalistyczna, 1944:3 (Folder 8)
          - Mlodziez Wiejska, 1944 March (Folder 9)
          - Mysl Robotnicza, 1944:1-4 (Folder 10)
          - Nakazy, 1944 May-June (Folder 11)
          - Narodowe Sily Zbrojne, 1943-1944 (Folder 12)
          - Orka, 1944 June (Folder 13)
          - Pobudka, 1944 (Folder 14)
          - Pochodnia
            - General, 1944 March-April (Folder 15)
            - Gospodarka Planowa (Folder 16)
            - Szkola Spoleczna (Folder 17)
          - Polska Gospodarcza, 1944 March (Folder 18)
          - Polska Ludowa, 1944 (Folder 19)
          - Prawda Dnia, 1944 (Folder 20)
          - Przeglad Polski, 1944 (Folder 21)
          - Przez Walke do Zwyciestwa, 1943-1944 (Folder 22)
          - Rapp: Regionalna Agencja Prasowa Podlasie, 1944 April (Folder 23)
          - Robotnik w Walce, 1944 January-September (Folder 24)
          - Rzeczpospolita Polska
            - 1943 September (Folder 25)
            - 1944 March (Folder 26)
          - Serwis, 1944 April (Box 34, Folder 1)
          - Swit, 1944 July (Folder 2)
          - Sztuka I Narod, 1944 January (Folder 3)
          - W.R.N., 1943-1944 (Folder 4)
          - Walka
            - General
              - 1943 (Folder 5)
              - 1944 (Folder 6)
            - Report on Ukraine, 1944 (Folder 7)
          - Wiarus, 1944 July (Folder 8)
          - Wielka Polska, 1944 April (Folder 9)
          - Wies, 1944 May-June (Folder 10)
          - Wies i Miasto, 1944 February (Folder 11)
          - Wschod, 1944 February (Folder 12)
          - Wzlot, 1943 October (Folder 13)
          - Zywia: Pismo Kobiet, 1943 October (Folder 14)
      - Publications
        - Podstawowe Zasady Demokracji, n.d. Biblioteka Plomieni (Folder 15)
        - Der Weg zum Sieg: Aufstand als Kunst, n.d. (tactics of communist struggle) (Folder 16)
        - Totaler Terror: Polen an Marterpfahl, 1943 (?) (Folder 17)
      - Reports
        - "Raport Sytuacyjny"
          - 1940-1941 (Box 35, Folder 1)
          - 1944 (Lithuania) (Folder 2)
        - Sprawozdanie Wspolnoty Interesow Gorniczo-Hutniczych: Spolka Akcyjna Katowice z Dzialalnosci za rok 1937 (Folder 3)
        - "Sprawozdanie Sytuacyjne z Kraju"
          - 1939-1941, volume 1 (Folder 4)
          - 1942-1943, volume 3 (Folder 5)
        - Untitled report on Edward R. Stettinius's economic interests in Europe, n.d. (Folder 6)
        - "Uwagi o naszej polityce miedzynarodowej," n.d. (Folder 7)
        - "Wieksze Niemieckie Koncerny Elektryczne," 1944 (Folder 8)
    - Akcja Kontynentalna
      - General
        - 1942 (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - 1943
          - General (Folder 2)
          - May-June (Folder 3)
        - 1944
          - June (Folder 4)
          - September (Folder 5)
          - October-November (Folder 6)
      - Karski, Jan - First mission to Poland, 1940. Typescript of account
        - Biographical note (Folder 7)
        - Chapters
          - 1. "Podroz autora" (Folder 8)
          - 2. "Sytuacja ogolna w kraju" (Folder 9)
          - 3. "Wybrane zagadnienia polityczno-ideowe w kraju" (Folder 10)
          - 4. "Zagadnienie Zydowskie w kraju" (Folder 11)
      - Lisbon outpost, 1942 (Folder 12)
    - Departments
      - Informacji (Information)
        - Political life in Poland, 1944 (Folder 13)
        - Propaganda (Folder 14)
      - Likwidacji Skutkow Wojny (War Losses)
        - Cieszyn, Duchy of (Folder 15)
        - Cultural losses, Reparations for (Folder 16)
        - Post-war order. Documents
          - Nos. 1-80 (Folder 17)
          - Nos. 81-176 (Folder 18)
          - Nos. 177-257 (Folder 19)
        - Reich's Eastern territories (Folder 20)
        - Western border (Folder 21)
      - Robot Publicznych (Public Works). Report, 1943 (Folder 22)
      - Rolnictwa - Land reform
        - General
          - General, 1943 (Folder 23)
          - Decree (Folder 24)
        - Agriculture, State of, 1944 (Box 37, Folder 1)
        - Land ownership by ethnic groups (Folder 2)
      - Skarbu (Finance)
        - Documents
          - List (Folder 3)
          - Nos. 1-8 (Folder 4)
          - Nos. 9-14 (Folder 5)
          - Nos. 15-22 (Folder 6)
        - Reports, 1944 (Folder 7)
      - Spraw Wewnetrznych (Interior)
        - Korpus Bezpieczenstwa (Folder 8)
        - Policja Panstwowa (Folder 9)
        - Program Spoleczno-Ekonomiczny, 1943 (Folder 10)
        - Sluzba Bezpieczenstwa, 1943 (Folder 11)
        - Tymczasowa Administracja Rzadowa, 1944 (Folder 12)
      - Sprawiedliwosci (Justice), 1943
        - Adwokatura, 1943 (Folder 13)
        - War crimes, 1943 (Folder 14)
    - Radio station Swit
      - Correspondence
        - 1942
          - September
            - General (Box 38, Folder 1)
            - Onion skin letter from Warsaw (Folder 2)
          - November (Folder 3)
          - December (Folder 4)
        - 1943
          - January (Folder 5)
          - February (Folder 6)
          - April (Folder 7)
          - May (Folder 8)
          - June (Folder 9)
          - July (Folder 10)
          - August (Folder 11)
          - September (Folder 12)
          - October (Folder 13)
          - November (Folder 14)
          - December (Folder 15)
        - 1944 (Folder 16)
      - Dispatches from intelligence outposts
        - General, 1943 March-1944 July (Folder 17)
        - Kazia, 1943 March-1944 July (Folder 18)
        - N, Naples (pages numbered and in chronological order)
          - 1943
            - March (Folder 19)
            - March-November (Folder 20)
            - April (Folder 21)
            - May (Folder 22)
            - May-August (Folder 23)
            - June (Folder 24)
            - July (Box 39, Folder 1)
            - August (Folder 2)
            - September (Folder 3)
            - October (Folder 4)
            - November (Folder 5)
          - 1943 September-1944 March (Folder 6)
          - 1944
            - April-July (Folder 7)
            - June-July (Folder 8)
            - August-October (Folder 9)
        - R and R 2, Rome
          - 1943
            - March (Folder 10)
            - August-November (Folder 11)
            - December (Folder 12)
          - 1944
            - January (Folder 13)
            - February (Folder 14)
            - March (Folder 15)
            - March-April (Folder 16)
            - April-June (Folder 17)
      - Instructions on Zwiazek Patriotow Polskich, 1944 May (Folder 18)
      - Reports - "Dzialalnosc wladz okupacyjnych na terytorium Rzeczypospolitej za okres od 1 IX 1939 do 1 XI 1940: Streszczenie," 1941 (Folder 19)
    - Regierung des Generalgouvernements [Poland (Territory under German occupation, 1939-1945)], Innere Verwaltung. Instruction on treatment of Poles, 1944 May (Folder 20)
  - Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Ministry of Foreign Affairs)
    - General - "Stosunki Polsko-Sowieckie od Wrzesnia 1939 roku do Kwietnia 1943 roku: Zbior dokumentow," London, 1943. Typescript
      - List
        - Chronological (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - Subject (Folder 2)
      - Parts
        - 1, pages 1-27 (Folder 3)
        - 2, pages 28-77 (Folder 4)
        - 3, pages 78-129 (Folder 5)
        - 4, pages 130-174 (Folder 6)
        - 5, pages 175-233 (Folder 7)
        - 6, pages 234-316 (Folder 8)
    - Countries
      - Canada, 1944 (Folder 9)
      - China, 1942 (Folder 10)
      - Czechoslovakia
        - 1943 (Folder 11)
        - 1945. Farewell letter from Stepan Osusky and Edvard Benes (Folder 12)
      - France, Vichy, 1941 (Folder 13)
      - Great Britain
        - 1940 - Treaties and talks (Folder 14)
        - 1941 - Relations with Germany (Folder 15)
        - 1942 (Folder 16)
        - 1943-1944 (Folder 17)
      - Hungary, 1940 (Folder 18)
      - Japan, 1941 (Folder 19)
      - Latvia, 1940 - Conditions in Poland (Folder 20)
      - Lithuania
        - 1939 (Folder 21)
        - 1941-1942 (Folder 22)
      - Palestine, 1941-1942 (Folder 23)
      - Romania, 1939 - Conditions in Poland (Folder 24)
      - Soviet Union
        - 1941 (Folder 25)
        - 1942 (Folder 26)
        - 1943 (Folder 27)
      - Turkey, 1941 (Folder 28)
      - United States, 1941-1943
        - General (Folder 29)
        - Drohojowski, Jan, Case of (Folder 30)
      - Vatican (Catholic Church), 1942 (Folder 31)
      - Yugoslavia, 1942 (Folder 32)
    - German occupation zone of Poland
      - General
        - "Dzialalnosc wladz okupacyjnych na terytorium Rzeczpospolitej za okres od 1 IX 1939 do 1 XI 1940," 1941. Typescript (Box 41, Folder 1)
        - "Ja jestem milion" by Zajdler, n.d. Typescript on Poland in 1939 (Folder 2)
      - Assistance to Poland
        - General
          - 1942 (Folder 3)
          - 1943 (Folder 4)
          - 1944 (Folder 5)
        - Swedish channels
          - 1942 (Folder 6)
          - 1943 (Folder 7)
          - 1944 (Folder 8)
      - Banking system (Folder 9)
      - Concentration camps - "Lists of Different Types of Concentration Camps for Poles," 1943. Typescript (Folder 10)
      - Destruction and pillage - "Prowizoryczne zestawienie strat Panstwa Polskiego sporzadzone na koniec lutego 1940 r. (Pierwsze przyblizenie)," n.d. Typescript (Folder 11)
      - Invasion of September 1939. German appeals to soldiers and general population (Folder 12)
      - Political developments in 1939-1940 (Folder 13)
      - Public executions. Announcements, 1943-1944 (Folder 14)
      - Ukrainians
        - "Ukrainska polityka niemieckich wladz okupacyjnych na terenie Reichskommisariat Ukraine," 1945. Typescript (Folder 15)
        - "Ukraina sowiecka," n.d., by S. Bida. Typescript (Folder 16)
    - German problem, Views of Polish Christian Social Movement on, 1944 (Folder 17)
    - Gralinski, Zygmunt, Case of, 1940 (Folder 18)
    - Jewish passports of South American origin, 1944 (Folder 19)
    - Ministers
      - Raczynski, Edward, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Romer, Tadeusz
        - General (Folder 2)
        - Correspondence
          - Great Britain. Foreign Office, 1944 (Folder 3)
          - Poland. Ambasada (United States), 1944 October-November (Folder 4)
      - Tarnowski, Adam - Dismissal of ambassador Stefan Glaser (Folder 5)
    - Poland. Ambasada (Soviet Union)
      - General
        - Appeal to the Poles scattered on Soviet territory, 1941 (Folder 6)
        - Correspondence
          - 1941
            - August. Includes reports (Folder 7)
            - September (Folder 8)
            - October (Folder 9)
            - November
              - 1-15. Includes transcripts of talks (Folder 10)
              - 16-30 (Folder 11)
            - December (Folder 12)
          - 1942
            - January-February (Folder 13)
            - March-April (Folder 14)
            - May-June (Folder 15)
            - July-August (Folder 16)
            - September-November (Folder 17)
          - 1943 (Folder 18)
        - Lists
          - Auditors of Polish Armed Forces (Folder 19)
          - Embassy officers, 1941 (Folder 20)
        - Minutes - Jaruszewicz, Mikolaj - Kot, Stanislaw, on status of Orthodox Church, 1941 December (Folder 21)
        - Political analysis - Soviet Union in 1941 (Folder 22)
        - Press review, 1941 September-October (Folder 23)
        - Reports
          - Agriculture, Soviet - Losses after German invasion, 1942 (Folder 24)
          - Catholics and Catholic Church, 1941 (Folder 25)
          - History
            - "Polska i Rosja" by Grabski, n.d. Typescript (Folder 26)
            - "Polska przed 1926 a w roku 1926," 1942, by Wladyslaw Kuczewski. Typescript (Folder 27)
      - Dzial Opieki Spolecznej (Department of Social Welfare)
        - General
          - Instructions for liaison officers, 1942 September-1941 January (Folder 28)
          - List of Polish inmates to be released as top priority (Folder 29)
          - Maps of camps (Folder 30)
          - Reports